<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Sun Woo Kim</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><copyright>sunwoo-kim [at] outlook [dot] com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/icon_hu8b309a9302268010949630654373c3a0_79828_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Many-body localization in bosons</title>
      <link>/project/mblbosons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/mblbosons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details open&gt; &lt;summary&gt; &lt;b&gt;What is this about?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;(click to open and close)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In usual circumstances, we expect systems to &amp;lsquo;thermalize&amp;rsquo; - for example, when we put espresso and milk together, we expect the two types of particles to mix, eventually resulting in a homogeneous mixture that we call latte.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also systems that do not thermalize. Many non-interacting systems do not thermalize, since the individual parts cannot talk to each other and therefore cannot mix. An Anderson Localized (AL) system is such a system, where non-interacting particles are &amp;lsquo;localized&amp;rsquo;, i.e. they do not venture far away from their initial positions. In other words, they retain a memory of their initial states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naively, we expect that interacting systems to thermalize. What is somewhat unexpected, then, is that in certain situations, even interacting particles can stay localized and not thermalize. These are called Many-Body Localized (MBL) phases and is a big part of condensed matter research today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People usually study this phenomenon on a lattice - they pixelize space, so that instead of continuous positions that particles can be in, there are discrete &amp;lsquo;sites&amp;rsquo;, or &amp;lsquo;boxes&amp;rsquo; that particles can be in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experimental physicists often study MBL systems using particles called Bosons, which are particles that can stack on top of each other in each site, compared to Fermions, which only allows one particle per site. But it&amp;rsquo;s much harder to study Bosons theoretically or computationally. Why? Well, if you think about the possible states for Fermions, there can either be a particle or no particle per site, so there are $2 \times 2 \times \cdots \times 2 = 2^L$ possible states, where $L$ is the number of sites. However, for Bosons, if there are $N$ particles in total, there can be 0 to $N$ particles per site, so there are $(N+1)^L$ possible states. As you have more particles, there are just way more possible states for Bosons compared to Fermions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this work, we developed a way to study Bosonic MBL systems efficiently. It is a bit hard to explain, but put in analogies, it goes something like this. A non-interacting quantum system can be thought of as a collection of pendulums, each with their own frequency. In the roughest approximation, the interactions will only change the frequencies of these pendulums. This approximation is called &amp;lsquo;Poincaré-Lindstedt&amp;rsquo; perturbation theory. We find that even this most basic approximation is enough to show some of the hallmarks of MBL systems, such as spreading of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what is conveyed in the cover photo. In the x-axis is space, where if it is lit up, it indicates that information was transmitted. The y-axis is &amp;lsquo;log-time&amp;rsquo;, such that as you go further and further, the time increases exponentially, from 10 to 100 to 1000 and so on. On the left is the non-interacting Anderson Localized system, and on the right is the interacting MBL system. We can see that because the particles interact, information is transmitted, albeit very slowly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like to know more about the work, please check out the PDF, which links to an ArXiv page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt; &lt;summary&gt; &lt;b&gt;Abstract&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;(click to open and close)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent experiments in quantum simulators have provided evidence for the Many-Body Localized (MBL) phase in 1D and 2D bosonic quantum matter. The theoretical study of such bosonic MBL, however, is a daunting task due to the unbounded nature of its Hilbert space. In this work, we introduce a method to compute the long-time real-time evolution of 1D and 2D bosonic systems in an MBL phase at strong disorder and weak interactions. We focus on local dynamical indicators that are able to distinguish an MBL phase from an Anderson localized phase. In particular, we consider the temporal fluctuations of local observables, the spatiotemporal behavior of two-time correlators and Out-Of-Time-Correlators (OTOCs). We show that these few-body observables can be computed with a computational effort that depends only polynomially on system size but is independent of the target time, by extending a recently proposed numerical method &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.aps.org/prb/abstract/10.1103/PhysRevB.99.241114&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[Phys. Rev. B &lt;strong&gt;99&lt;/strong&gt;, 241114 (2019)]&lt;/a&gt; to mixed states and bosons. Our method also allows us to surrogate our numerical study with analytical considerations of the time-dependent behavior of the studied quantities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonsymmorphic crystals and topological waveguiding</title>
      <link>/project/nonsymmorphic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/nonsymmorphic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details open&gt; &lt;summary&gt; &lt;b&gt;What is this about?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;(click to open and close)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are probably well aware of tiles on the sidewalk or wallpapers with patterns that repeat themselves, potentially forever. There is some kind of symmetry there, but how do we describe it? Mathematicians were able to codeify these patterns using a field called &amp;lsquo;group theory&amp;rsquo;. In group theory, we define symmetries as transformations that leave the pattern the same, in other words, invariant. For example, assuming that the pattern goes on forever, we can shift the repeating pattern of wallpapers by certain directions and amount can retrieve the same exact pattern as before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In physics, systems that repeat themselves forever are called crystals. What&amp;rsquo;s cool about crystals is that the symmetries of the crystals have a direct impact on how waves propagating in the crystals themselves behave, such as if we were to shine light (famously known as a wave) through it, or disturb it (resulting in a sound wave) and so on. Only knowing the symmetries of the crystal, we can predict whether a wave propagating in the crystal will spread out evenly, or propagate in a highly directed fashion, such as in the cover photo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In wallpapers or sidewalks, there are two different kind of symmetries. The first is symmorphic symmetry, where there exists two kinds of separable symmetries: translational, shifting the entire pattern, and rotational, only rotating the entire pattern around certain points. Nonsymmorphic symmetries are a bit more complicated, in that you cannot separate out the translational and rotational symmetries; there are certain symmetries that require partial translation, followed by a rotation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, we predicted how certain crystals would behave based on their symmetries, and used their properties to design &amp;lsquo;waveguides&amp;rsquo;, that are able to steer the waves around in particular directions efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like to know more about the work, please check out the PDF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- Now let&#39;s tackle the &#39;topological waveguiding&#39; part of the title. What does this mean? This part is a bit more complicated. To put it simply, we first need to go into wavevector space. This is an abstract space where instead of the coordinates being points in real space, the coordinates are instead possible waves with wavelengths and directions that can propagate in the system. --&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;details&gt; &lt;summary&gt; &lt;b&gt;Abstract&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;(click to open and close)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study of wave propagation through structured periodic media depends critically upon the periodic lattice from which the medium is constructed. That is unsurprising, but perhaps what is slightly more surprising, is that pieces of pure mathematics play a key role - in particular, group and representation theory. Group theory is the natural language that encodes the symmetries of shape and form. Here we use it to consider a class of $2D$ periodic crystals whose lattice is encoded by &lt;em&gt;nonsymmorphic&lt;/em&gt; space groups. These are often overlooked due to their relative complexity compared to the symmorphic space groups. We demonstrate that nonsymmorphic groups have possible practical interest in terms of coalescence of dispersion curves, Dirac points and band-sticking, using both theory and simulation. Once we&amp;rsquo;ve laid out the group theoretical framework in the context of the nonsymmorphic crystals, we use it to illustrate how accidental degeneracies can arise in symmorphic square lattices. We combine this phenomenon with topological valley effects to design highly-efficient topological waveguides and energy-splitters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
