<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Sun Woo P. Kim</title>
    <link>https://sunwoo-kim.github.io/en/projects/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://sunwoo-kim.github.io/en/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>swk34 [at] cantab [dot] ac [dot] uk</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://sunwoo-kim.github.io/media/icon_hu8b309a9302268010949630654373c3a0_79828_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://sunwoo-kim.github.io/en/projects/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-osculating walks and surfaces</title>
      <link>https://sunwoo-kim.github.io/en/projects/osculating/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sunwoo-kim.github.io/en/projects/osculating/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum inference problems and quantum hidden Markov models</title>
      <link>https://sunwoo-kim.github.io/en/projects/quantuminference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sunwoo-kim.github.io/en/projects/quantuminference/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydrodynamics in deterministic circuits</title>
      <link>https://sunwoo-kim.github.io/en/projects/gateshydro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sunwoo-kim.github.io/en/projects/gateshydro/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The planted directed polymer; inferring a random walk from noisy images</title>
      <link>https://sunwoo-kim.github.io/en/projects/plantedpolymer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sunwoo-kim.github.io/en/projects/plantedpolymer/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super long-time dynamics of many-body localised bosons</title>
      <link>https://sunwoo-kim.github.io/en/projects/mblbosons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sunwoo-kim.github.io/en/projects/mblbosons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details open&gt; &lt;summary&gt; &lt;b&gt;For the general public&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;(click to open and close)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we put espresso and milk together, we expect the two types of particles to mix, eventually resulting in a homogeneous mixture that we call latte. This phenomenon is called ‘thermalization’. In usual circumstances, we expect systems to thermalize, where a ‘system’ is simply a set of governing rules and agents. In our case of coffee and milk, the governing rules would be the physics of fluids, and the agents would be the coffee and milk particles.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
There are also systems that do not thermalize. Non-interacting systems are a common example of non-thermalizing systems, since the individual particles cannot talk to each other and therefore cannot mix. One important non-interacting system is an ‘Anderson Localized’ (AL) one, where non-interacting particles are ‘localized’, i.e. they do not venture far away from their initial positions. In other words, they retain a memory of their initial states.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Naively, we expect that interacting systems to thermalize. What is somewhat unexpected, then, is that in certain situations, even interacting particles can stay localized and not thermalize. These are called ‘Many-Body Localized’ (MBL) systems and are a big part of condensed matter physics research today. Theorists usually study such phenomena on a lattice. A lattice is a simplification of space, so that instead of particles being in continuous positions, they occupy discrete ‘sites’, which are states that particles can be in.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In physics, there are two types of fundamental particles. The first are ‘fermions’, which are particles where only one particle can occupy a given site, much like the game of musical chairs. The second are ‘bosons’, where any number of particles can occupy a single site at a time. In the musical chairs analogy, it would be as if multiple players could sit on top of a single chair. Experimentalists have recently been studying MBL systems using bosons. However, both theoretically and computationally, bosons are much harder to solve compared to fermions. Why? Well, if you think about the possible states for fermions, there can either be a particle or no particle per site, so there are $2 \times 2 \times \cdots \times 2 = 2^L$ possible states, where $L$ is the number of sites. However, for bosons, if there are $N$ particles in total, there can be 0 to $N$ particles per site, so there are $(N+1)^L$  possible states. As you have more particles, there are simply more possible states for bosons compared to fermions.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In our work, we developed a way to study bosonic MBL systems efficiently. The method is quite abstract, but can be explained with the following analogy. A non-interacting quantum system can be thought of as a collection of pendulums, each located on a site in the lattice and each with their own frequency. Each pendulum only affects their own weights, each oscillating with their own frequency as they swing, without getting in the way of pendulums in other sites. In the roughest approximation, the interactions will only change the frequencies of these pendulums. This approximation is called ‘Poincaré-Lindstedt’ theory. By applying this theory/principle in our  analyses of bosonic MBL systems, we found that even the most basic approximation is enough to show some of the hallmarks of MBL systems.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
One of the hallmarks of MBL systems is the slow spreading of information due to the interactions of the particles. The above cover photo depicts a lattice. On the left is the non-interacting AL system, and on the right is the interacting MBL system. The x-axis is space, and the y-axis is ‘log-time’, where time increases exponentially as you go further up the graph, from 1 to 10 to 100 and so on. The areas where the lattice/graph is lit up indicates that information was transmitted. We can see that in the case of the AL system, the spread of information is stunted, but in the case of the MBL system, because the particles interact, information is transmitted, albeit very slowly, since you need to wait an exponentially longer time for information to spread to the next site.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
If you’d like to know more about this work, please check out the PDF link, which links to the pdf at Physics Review B.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt; &lt;summary&gt; &lt;b&gt;Abstract&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;(click to open and close)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent experiments in quantum simulators have provided evidence for the Many-Body Localized (MBL) phase in 1D and 2D bosonic quantum matter. The theoretical study of such bosonic MBL, however, is a daunting task due to the unbounded nature of its Hilbert space. In this work, we introduce a method to compute the long-time real-time evolution of 1D and 2D bosonic systems in an MBL phase at strong disorder and weak interactions. We focus on local dynamical indicators that are able to distinguish an MBL phase from an Anderson localized phase. In particular, we consider the temporal fluctuations of local observables, the spatiotemporal behavior of two-time correlators and Out-Of-Time-Correlators (OTOCs). We show that these few-body observables can be computed with a computational effort that depends only polynomially on system size but is independent of the target time, by extending a recently proposed numerical method &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.aps.org/prb/abstract/10.1103/PhysRevB.99.241114&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[Phys. Rev. B &lt;strong&gt;99&lt;/strong&gt;, 241114 (2019)]&lt;/a&gt; to mixed states and bosons. Our method also allows us to surrogate our numerical study with analytical considerations of the time-dependent behavior of the studied quantities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MASt Thesis - Metric tomography with Sobolev gradients</title>
      <link>https://sunwoo-kim.github.io/en/projects/sobolev/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sunwoo-kim.github.io/en/projects/sobolev/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details open&gt; &lt;summary&gt; &lt;b&gt;For the general public&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;(click to open and close)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though the &amp;lsquo;metric tensor&amp;rsquo; seems like an exotic object that only exist in general relativity, it&amp;rsquo;s actually just a tool to describe effective distances. For example, it could be used to describe time that sound waves take, like inside of the Earth! This could be anisotropic, meaning that sound could be faster in one direction than the other. The speed of sound waves are determined by a myriad of factors, such as density and composition.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The next (practical) question is, how do we determine the composition given that we have measured some sound waves at certain locations? Given a metric tensor, we have the &amp;lsquo;forward&amp;rsquo; equation that predicts how sound waves will travel, but now we are describing an &amp;lsquo;inverse&amp;rsquo; problem where we want to determine the metric tensor with essentially infinite parameters given some finite measurements. How do we do this? A basic way to do this is to use finite parameterisation and use regularisation to constrain the model. A better way is to work in function space and calculate &lt;em&gt;functional&lt;/em&gt; derivatives, then do gradient descent. Practically speaking, we resolve them via Fourier kernels, but this is fine, since after this we can increase the number of Fourier kernels until the solution converges.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
We want to impose any assumptions/knowledge we have about the solution. For example, point-wise convergence and some levels of differentiability are probably good assumptions. To constrain solutions to have such properties, we can work in specific functions spaces &amp;ndash; Sobolev spaces are such spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt; &lt;summary&gt; &lt;b&gt;Abstract&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;(click to open and close)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In underdetermined inverse problems such as ray-tracing tomography, finite-parametrisation of the model and regularisation of the misfit functional are often used to force a unique solution. However, these measures are unsatisfactory because they are arbitrarily chosen. An alternative method is to use gradient-based optimisation to find a local minimum of the misfit, where the first order gradient of the misfit is required for the scheme and the second order can be used to quantify the constraints on the obtained solution or to potentially improve the scheme. The adjoint method is an effective way of calculating these gradients. We show that, in order to obtain a sensible solution through this scheme, we must work in an appropriate Sobolev space, the space of square-integrable functions with additional continuity constraints. We apply these ideas to the metric tomographic problem, the problem of finding an unknown metric on a manifold given a finite number of geodesics, which is an analogous problem to ray-tracing tomography of surface waves. We numerically implement this method for the linearised version of the problem on a 2-dimensional torus. Additionally, we present the first and second adjoints for the general problem, which can be used to calculate the first and second order gradients of the misfit function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonsymmorphic crystals and topological waveguiding</title>
      <link>https://sunwoo-kim.github.io/en/projects/nonsymmorphic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sunwoo-kim.github.io/en/projects/nonsymmorphic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details open&gt; &lt;summary&gt; &lt;b&gt;For the general public&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;(click to open and close)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are probably well aware of tiles on the sidewalk or wallpapers with patterns that repeat themselves, potentially forever. There is some kind of symmetry there, but how do we describe it? Mathematicians were able to codify these patterns using a field called &amp;lsquo;group theory&amp;rsquo;. In group theory, we define symmetries as transformations that leave the pattern the same, in other words, invariant. For example, assuming that the pattern goes on forever, we can shift the repeating pattern of wallpapers by certain directions and amount can retrieve the same exact pattern as before.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In physics, systems that repeat themselves forever are called crystals. What&amp;rsquo;s cool about crystals is that the symmetries of the crystals have a direct impact on how waves propagating in the crystals themselves behave, such as if we were to shine light (famously known as a wave) through it, or disturb it (resulting in a sound wave) and so on. Only knowing the symmetries of the crystal, we can predict whether a wave propagating in the crystal will spread out evenly, or propagate in a highly directed fashion, such as in the cover photo.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In wallpapers or sidewalks, there are two different kinds of symmetries. The first is symmorphic symmetry, where there exists two kinds of separable symmetries: translational, shifting the entire pattern, and rotational, only rotating the entire pattern around certain points. Nonsymmorphic symmetries are a bit more complicated, in that you cannot separate out the translational and rotational symmetries; there are certain symmetries that require partial translation, followed by a rotation.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In this project, we predicted how certain crystals would behave based on their symmetries, and used their properties to design &amp;lsquo;waveguides&amp;rsquo;, that are able to steer the waves around in particular directions efficiently.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
If you like to know more about the work, please check out the PDF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- Now let&#39;s tackle the &#39;topological waveguiding&#39; part of the title. What does this mean? This part is a bit more complicated. To put it simply, we first need to go into wavevector space. This is an abstract space where instead of the coordinates being points in real space, the coordinates are instead possible waves with wavelengths and directions that can propagate in the system. --&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;details&gt; &lt;summary&gt; &lt;b&gt;Abstract&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;(click to open and close)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study of wave propagation through structured periodic media depends critically upon the periodic lattice from which the medium is constructed. That is unsurprising, but perhaps what is slightly more surprising, is that pieces of pure mathematics play a key role - in particular, group and representation theory. Group theory is the natural language that encodes the symmetries of shape and form. Here we use it to consider a class of $2D$ periodic crystals whose lattice is encoded by &lt;em&gt;nonsymmorphic&lt;/em&gt; space groups. These are often overlooked due to their relative complexity compared to the symmorphic space groups. We demonstrate that nonsymmorphic groups have possible practical interest in terms of coalescence of dispersion curves, Dirac points and band-sticking, using both theory and simulation. Once we&amp;rsquo;ve laid out the group theoretical framework in the context of the nonsymmorphic crystals, we use it to illustrate how accidental degeneracies can arise in symmorphic square lattices. We combine this phenomenon with topological valley effects to design highly-efficient topological waveguides and energy-splitters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing network models</title>
      <link>https://sunwoo-kim.github.io/en/projects/networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sunwoo-kim.github.io/en/projects/networks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details open&gt; &lt;summary&gt; &lt;b&gt;For the general public&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;(click to open and close)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing network models are simple models that model social settings. For example, it could model how much research papers are cited - people tend to cite papers that are already cited (preferential attachment). This effect by itself leads to winner-takes-all effects, with winners randomly chosen due to random fluctuations. We study some of the models and come up with more accurate expressions for certain limits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt; &lt;summary&gt; &lt;b&gt;Abstract&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;(click to open and close)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three growing network models (GNMs) are studied numerically using Monte Carlo sampling and analytically using mean-field approximation. The first is the Barabási-Albert (BA)/PurePref model, where new nodes are connected preferentially connected to existing nodes with many preexisting links. The second is the PureRand model, where there is no preference. The third is the Mixed model, where node choice probability is chosen between the two models. Apart from rederivation of known results, our original contribution is as follows. We study the node degree evolution directly instead of the steady state distribution, to find an analytic form more accurate with number of edges added per timestep, $m$. We confirm the results with numerics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BSc Thesis - Coulomb branch of 𝓝 = 4, 𝑑 = 2 &#43; 1 supersymmetric gauge field theories</title>
      <link>https://sunwoo-kim.github.io/en/projects/quivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sunwoo-kim.github.io/en/projects/quivers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details open&gt; &lt;summary&gt; &lt;b&gt;For the general public&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;(click to open and close)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The famous Higgs mechanism, where a scalar (Higgs) field chooses one of the degenerate minima, gives particles their mass. In so-called supersymmetric gauge field theories, the space of degenerate minima is called the moduli space. Information about the moduli space is encoded in diagrams called &amp;lsquo;quiver diagrams&amp;rsquo; and an algebraic series called the Hilbert series. We studied the structure of these moduli spaces for a particular set of these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt; &lt;summary&gt; &lt;b&gt;Abstract&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;(click to open and close)&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moduli space of a gauge ﬁeld theory is an abstract space of vacuum expectation values
of scalar fields. It is of physical signiﬁcance as a point in this space must be chosen
before the masses of particles can be determined. For $\mathcal{N} = 4$, $d = 2 + 1$ supersymmetric
gauge fields theories, whose information can be encoded in quiver diagrams, there are
two branches in its moduli space: the Higgs branch and the Coulomb branch, where
the latter can be calculated using the monopole formula. In this article, the Coulomb
branch of $A_n$, $C_n$, $F_4$, $G_2$ Dynkin quivers and their affine counterparts were studied by
calculating their Hilbert series using the monopole formula. In addition to conﬁrming
previous predictions, new implications on the choice of ungauging location (ﬁxing one of
the phases) were found, which we state as the &lt;em&gt;ungauging hypothesis&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
